Contact

fernjess8@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jessica-fern-89b78488 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Neurosurgery

Surgery

ICU

Languages

English

Certifications

Adult-Gerontology Acute Care NP - Board Certified

Critical Care Registered Nurse (CCRN)

200 Registered Yoga Teacher

Jessica Fern

CVICU Acute Care Nurse Practitioner at Cleveland Clinic Cleveland, Ohio

Summary

Experienced Nurse Practitioner with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Cardiothoracic Surgery, Neurosurgery, Intensive Care, Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Critical Care, and Healthcare. Strong healthcare services professional with a Master of Science in Nursing (MSN) focused in Adult Acute Care Nursing from The University of Pennsylvania.

Experience

Cleveland Clinic
CVICU Acute Care Nurse Practitioner
December 2016 - Present (3 years 7 months)
Cleveland. Ohio

Nurse Practitioner in the Cardiovascular Surgical Intensive Care Unit

University of Pennsylvania

1 year 8 months

Adjunct Faculty
August 2016 - December 2016 (5 months)

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner student May 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 4 months)

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

Duke University Health System Registered Nurse January 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 5 months)

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

Provide nursing care in the immediate post-operative period to critically ill
patients, including CABG, heart valve replacement/repair, heart transplants,
and lung transplants.

- Collaborate with the medical staff, including physicians, respiratory therapists, physical therapists, and families to provide exceptional patient care, leading to optimal patient outcomes.
- Continuously recognized by management for leadership roles by being placed on a fast track for highly skilled medical device certifications.
- Continue to be lauded by patients and family members for highly effective communication, safety, and exceptional patient care.
- Educate staff as EPIC system resource based on years of EPIC training and usage in the clinical field.

Get Real Health

Intern

June 2014 - August 2014 (3 months)

Rockville, Maryland

- Collaborate directly with the Vice President, Senior Healthcare Strategist, and Product Development team on healthcare policy research and product development for the company's Instant Personal Health Record (PHR) product.
- Provide detailed research on the international healthcare markets with clients in the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, Spain, Saudi Arabia, and Dubai.
- Participate in HIMSS-related and health IT policy conferences in Washington, DC.
- Contribute my nursing clinical expertise to the development of a patientfocused PHR.

Beaumont Health System Registered Nurse September 2010 - December 2012 (2 years 4 months) Royal Oak, Michigan

- Provided nursing care to critically ill patients, primarily post-operative CABG, heart valve replacement/repair, thoracic and peripheral vascular surgical patients.
- Administered and titrated vasoactive medications, leading to improved patient outcomes in the immediate post-operative period.
- Displayed teamwork by assisting physicians in bedside procedures including intubation, insertion of central and arterial lines, chest tubes, and tracheostomies.
- Demonstrated leadership by being part of the CPR team in nursing and diagnostic units throughout the hospital.
- EPIC certified and trained.

Henry Ford Health System

Registered Nurse

August 2009 - September 2010 (1 year 2 months)

West Bloomfield, Michigan

- Provided post-operative nursing care for patients with neurosurgical conditions including lumbar laminectomies, cervical discectomies, and craniotomies.
- Ensured safety and provided treatment for actively seizing patients in the Epilepsy Monitoring Unit.
- Displayed leadership by prioritizing and delegating assignments as charge nurse on the 32-bed neurosurgical unit beginning one week after orientation.
- Assessed and treated complications of patients continuously monitored on telemetry to ensure efficient discharge home.

Education

University of Pennsylvania

Master of Science (MS), Adult Health Nurse/Nursing · (2015 - 2016)

Michigan State University

Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2008 - 2009)

University of Miami

Bachelor of Science (BS), Motion Pictures/Political Science · (2003 - 2007)